# CODY JAY SCHNEIDER

336 Winding Woods Trail · Woodstock, GA · 30189 (706) 765-8463 cody.schneider@gmail.com

### **Professional Profile**

An accomplished Web Developer with 4 years professional experience and a life-long passion for technology and the Internet. A creative and determined individual with solid communication skills, sales experience, and technical expertise. Highly adaptable problem solver, driven to exceed goals and expectations by a desire to learn new things, overcome challenges, and stretch creative potential.

## **Core Competencies**

- Adoption and evangelism of industry standards and best practices for the development of accessible, high performance websites and web applications.
- Extensive knowledge of industry trends, Social Media APIs, ¡Query framework, and Open Source plug-in ecosystem.
- Responsive design and development with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Rapid concept prototyping and inventive vision.
- Developing strong professional relationships, managing multiple simultaneous projects, and collaborating with internal and external stake holders.

## **Career History**

[January 2011 – Present] – WebMD – Atlanta, GA

- Sr. Web Developer Contractor, Site Operations
  - Audited site for accessibility issues (WCAG 2.0 standards) and lead multiple initiatives for improvement, including development of a keyboard and screen reader accessible home page slideshow.
  - Core member of the working group responsible for prototyping the front end architecture of the next generation responsive redesign.
  - Mobile and tablet development: implementation of responsive images and touch interfaces.
  - Experience with Git source control and GitHub Enterprise.
  - Creation of custom modules using XSL, XSLT, and XML.

[December 2008 – January 2012] – FIS (previously Metavante Corporation) – Brown Deer, WI Web Developer – Consumer eBanking and Website Services

- Developed menu systems, data tables, forms, slideshows, and other custom interactive widgets using the jQuery framework and available plug-ins.
- Use of AJAX and the jQuery validation plug-in for complex live form validation.
- Established development standards for Website Services group including configuration of local development servers, new project templates, re-usable code snippets, and debugging practices.
- System Administration, Client Support, and development of custom skins and editing tools for the DotNetNuke Content Management and Web Application Framework.
- Prevention and debugging of cross browser CSS and JavaScript issues.

- Consulted with Enterprise Architecture group on UI development best practices and assisted with the creation of templates to be used as the corporate standard for next generation applications.
- Developed Proof of Concept for Enterprise Product Design and Usability group demonstrating the use of responsive design principles for applications that could run on Mobile and Desktop platforms.
- Lead developer for several cross departmental proof of concept and prototyping projects, including the company's first tablet offering.
- Consulted with clients and executive management on Social Media, mobile development, and analytics.
- Collaborated directly with clients and internal stake holders to determine project requirements, estimate costs, and establish delivery timelines.
- Managed multiple simultaneous projects while consistently meeting deadlines and delivering highest quality work.
- Firewall, DNS, and other system administration tasks for UNIX and Windows servers.

[January 2007 – December 2010] – W3bvision – Eagle, WI

Web Developer / Entrepreneur – www.w3bvision.com

- Developed dynamic and static sites using DotNetNuke, Drupal, and Wordpress Content Management Systems.
- Administration and setup of multi user LAMP server including FTP, SSH, and CMS services.
- Authored multimedia and text based content for small businesses.

[January 2004 – December 2004] - MC Custom Concepts - Brandon, FL

Entrepreneur - Hurricane Protection

- Designed website, graphics and ad copy for a successful advertising campaign using TV, print, and Internet media.
- Prepared and presented investment proposals which resulted in \$23,000 capital investments.
- Negotiated contracts and favorable buying agreements with advertisers, suppliers, and lenders.

[February 2003 – January 2004] - Generac Power Systems, Inc. - Whitewater, WI Dealership Recruiter - Home Standby Generators

- Generated sales of over \$1,000,000 from new accounts.
- Leading dealership recruiter during 5 consecutive record-breaking months and 9 consecutive months of new account growth from the previous year.

### Education

[August 2007 – April 2009] - Baker College - Flint, MI A.S. Web Design – **Summa Cum Laude**